Guide to the International Center for Transitional Justice (ICTJ) Records, 1981-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Accession (2009-0193), (76 boxes)
  - Staff files: Vasuki Nesiah (Box 34)
    - Workshop on Survey, May 2007
    - Ratna Kapur
    - Fionnuala Ni Aolain
    - Anne Orford
    - Katharine Franke
    - Jayne Huckerby, Gender and Transitional Justice modules
    - Yasmin Sooka-Foundation for Human Rights
    - Printing/copy edit
    - Nesiah's expenses, 2003-2006 (5 folders)
    - Conferences
    - Philippines
    - Miscellaneous emails, 2003
    - Accountability (Box 43)
    - Amnesties
    - Class action suits
    - Children and human rights
    - Conflict resolution
    - Constitutionalism
    - Corporations and human rights
    - Corruption
    - Democracy and transitional justice
    - Discrimination
    - Economic issues
    - Elections
    - Freedom of information
    - ICC
    - Innovations
    - Institutional reform
    - Islamic law
    - Unlabelled folder
    - CPU documents
    - Human rights/transitional justice history
  - History Memory Project materials, 1998-2006 (Box 44)
  - Policymakers and Civil Society Unit retreats, 2006-2008
  - Staff files: Elizabeth Goodfriend (Box 45)
    Program associate at the New York office, 2006-present.
    - CD: Peace song of the Liberia TRC
    - TRC in Liberia posters
    - Story of Sierra Rat posters
    - Notes on Liberia, general, and research unit, 2006-2008 (6 folders)
    - Liberian Working Group (spiral)
    - Liberian Truth and Reconciliation Project materials, 2007-2008 (3 folders)
  - Staff files: Priscilla Hayner (Box 46)
    - ICTJ Conference inventations, 2003-2004
    - Rolodex (Box 47)
    - Confidential binders, 2001
    - Notebooks
    - Computer discs
    - Crisis in Zimbabwe Coalition: Zimbabwe Report
    - Fundraising meeting agendas
    - Management meeting agendas
    - Intern folder: Omar Drammeh, Summer 2006
    - Invitations declined
    - South Korea update
    - Draft final reports: Landman, Dr. Todd
    - Another Child of Everyone manuscript by Ishmael Beah
    - Report of the Transitional Justice Workshop, 2004
    - ICTJ staff newsletters, 2006 (Box 48)
    - Correspondence, Encyclopedia of Human Rights
    - ICRC Truth Commissions chapter correspondence
    - AJIL guidelines for book reviews
    - Correspondence, Development in Practice
    - Unit meeting materials
    - Correspondence, management meetings
    - Agendas, management materials
    - Information Management materials
    - Correspondence, Bard BGIA
    - Truth Commissions and public hearings materials
    - Afterword (revised), Unspeakable Truths
    - Correspondence re: Hayner's book translation (Spanish)
    - Correspondence re: book translation (Arabic)
    - Final report, Todd Landman
    - French materials
    - Space/architects (Box 49)
    - Senior Associate search, 2002
    - Office furniture materials
    - To-do lists and forms (2 folders)
    - The Relationship between the TRC and the Special Court in Sierra Leone
    - ICTJ logo developments
    - ICTJ staff diagrams, 2000
    - Outreach
    - Partnership programs
    - The International Center for Transitional Justice: an Introduction
    - ICTJ internal memos
    - ICTJ retreat materials, 2002 (2 folders)
    - Tides Center materials
    - Budget materials, 2003
    - International IDEA Handbook authors agreement
    - ICTJ Press
    - ICTJ, Washington DC office launch pamphlet
    - Grant proposal, March 2001
    - Ford Foundation Grant award materials
    - Confidential files (2 folders)
    - Big Picture memos
    - ICTJ development documents
    - AFF-BET meeting documents
    - Correspondence with Peyi Soyinkaa-Airewele
    - Research projects and correspondence
    - ICTJ programs and agendas
    - Interns: records and CVs, Summer 2001
    - ICTJ 501(c)(3) documents
    - Information Management consulting project
    - Public speaking events attended, 2002
    - Zimbabwe trip materials, May 2002
    - Washington DC itinerary, October 2002
    - Washington DC materials, July-August 2001
    - Sierra Leone trip, July 2002
    - Itinerary, Washington DC, May 2002
    - Agenda, Greensboro meeting, March 2002
    - ICTJ Board Meetnig agenda and minutes, October 2002
    - Balkans Strategy
    - Africa internship program documents
    - Capacity building documents
    - Due process project
    - ICTJ publications
    - Inter-relationships
    - ICTJ Fellows program
    - Milosevic Video Project (Bard)
    - ICTJ Policymakers Program
    - Public speaking notes
    - ICRC Project: The Missing
    - Research Law Firms project and proposal
    - Research: Reparations project
    - Truth commission information
    - Transitional Justice Alliance
    - Research map materials
    - Andrus Family Fund materials, 2001-2003
    - Country tracking, 2001
    - Miscellaneous meetings
    - Peacekeeping projects
    - Correspondence re: West Africa Program
    - Correspondence: Conference reports
    - ICTJ Board of Directors Meeting materials, March 2003
    - Correspondence, UNDP
    - NYU Lessons Learned grant materials (3 folders)
    - ICTJ general information, budgets, policies (3 folders)
    - ICTJ Board of Directors Meeting materials, April 2002
    - Sierra Leone Truch Commission paper, drafts, and comments
    - Mexico Special Prosecutor paper, drafts, and comments
    - ICTJ Assistance documents, 2001-2002
    - Syllabus, Columbia University: Introduction to Human Rights, Fall 2003
    - Workshop on the Best Practices to Combat Impunity, 2003
    - Events attended, 2001
    - LASA Conference materials, September 2001
    - Trinity College Human Rights materials
    - EXCO materials
    - Country Files, A-L (Box 50)
      - Afghanistan
      - Algeria
      - Balkans
      - Bosnia
      - Brazil
      - Burma
      - Burundi
      - Cambodia
      - Chile
      - Colombia
      - Cuba
      - Congo
      - Cyprus
      - East Timor
      - El Salvador
      - Ethiopia
      - France
      - Ghana
      - Guatemala
      - Haiti
      - Honduras
      - Indonesia
      - Iran
      - Iraq
      - Ivory Coast
      - Israel/Palestine
      - Kosovo
      - Liberia
    - Country files, M-S (Box 51-52)
      - Madagascar
      - Mexico
      - Middle East program
      - Morocco
      - Nicaragua
      - Nigeria
      - Northern Ireland
      - Panama
      - Paraguay
      - Peru
      - Rwanda
      - Sierra Leone
    - Country files, S-Z (Box 53-54)
      - Sierra Leone
      - Solomon Islands
      - Somalia
      - South Africa
      - South Korea
      - Spain
      - Sri Lanka
      - Sudan
      - Thailand
      - Turkey/Armenia
      - Uruguay
      - United States: Greensboro
      - United States: Southern Truth Commission
      - Venezuela
      - Vietnam
      - Zimbabwe
    - Project files, A-O
      - 9/11 projects
      - AHTISAAR Initiative
      - Apologies
      - Chicago principles
      - Bosnia and Serbia papers
      - Children and armed conflict
      - Command responsibility
      - Complementarity
      - Corruption
      - Europe projects/contacts
      - Gender and transitional justice
      - Genocide encyclopedia
      - Hillel Levine projects
      - Innovations to Justice
      - Intelligence Oversight project
      - Land conflicts
      - Long-term legacies
      - IPU-Policymakers
      - IPU
      - MacArthur reviews
      - Memorials
      - Memory work
      - Naming names
      - Newsletter
      - Notre Dame book project proposal
      - O&A intelligence oversight
      - O&A research: mandatory reporting
      - OHCHR Toolkit project
    - Budget/Work Plan and miscellaneous files (Box 55)
      - Materials, 2002-2006 (5 binders)
      - Human Resources Policies and Procedures (1 binder)
      - ECXO past agendas
      - Zimbabwe conference, August 2001
      - Washington DC Law Group training, April 2001
      - UN University, November 2001
      - UNICEF meeting, June 2001
      - Sierra Leone, OHCHR
      - Aspen, June 2001
      - SIPA author's panel, December 2000
      - Public speaking classes, 2001
      - RIREC, September 2001
      - UN DPA paper
      - AAAS/CSVR conference, November 2002
      - ILA event, October 2002
      - AFSC event, June 2002
      - Cancun, April 2002
      - Carnegie Council: International Historical Initiative, February 2002
      - Carnegie Council workshop, January 2002
      - Ford, ICTJ planning grant
      - Greensboro meeting, October 2002
      - IPA conference on transitional administration, November 2002
      - IPA reintegration conference, December 2002
      - IPA Sierra Leone conference, June 2002
      - Ireland conference, September 2002
      - John Jay/Garzon dinner
      - Jose Ramos-Horta meeting, January 2002
      - Public speaking
      - Universal Jurisdiction meeting, February-March 2002
      - UNDPI/NGO conference, September 2002
      - UN Security Council briefing, March 2002
    - Fundraising and Trips (Box 56-57)
      - Organizational review with MAG
      - Work plan, 2005
      - Trip reports, 2004-2005
      - Program descriptions, 2004
      - Organizations (48 folders)
      - Trips, 2003-2005 (46 folders)
    - Projects, fundraising, and ICTJ organizational issues (Box 58)
      - Diane Orenthlicher report and submissions, 2003-2004 (2 folders)
      - Priscilla Hayner's book and publication materials (8 folders)
      - Reconciliation
      - Reviews by Priscilla Hayner (2 folders)
      - Summer Institute
      - Truth Commission funders
      - Transitional Justice Alliance
      - Trip reports, 2004
      - Tutu Fellowship
      - UK Initiative at the UN
      - UN-Transitional Justice issues
      - Universal jurisdiction
      - UN ROL/J report
      - USIP Truth Commission film
      - Vancouver dialogues
      - Website
      - Youth
      - Zimbabwe, 2003 (2 folders)
      - Fundraising
      - ICTJ organizational issues
      - Europe Office: Bill Seary report
      - European office
      - Four Unit meeting
      - Government funding
      - ICTJ evaluations
      - ICTJ Institutional Reform
      - ICTJ retreat
      - Management meetings (2 folders)
      - Office move
      - Judit Ponsada
      - ICTJ retreat, 2004
      - Visiting fellows
      - Work plan
      - Work planning, 2006
      - Info-sharing
      - Management Committee
      - ICTJ publishing policies
      - Summer 2002 interns
      - ICTJ history
      - Unfoldered miscellaneous materials (Box 59)
      - Policymakers (2 folders)
      - Kenya, 2002-2005 (5 folders)
      - Bern: Human rights in peace agreements, 2006
      - Spain, FRIDE conference, April 2006
      - Unfoldered miscellaneous, including correspondence, articles, itineraries, etc.
      - Current writing projects
      - O&A papers: Calendar
      - Argentina paper
      - Chile paper
      - Unofficial TR-SKG
      - US city-based initiatives
      - Pending
      - Trends paper
      - South Africa paper
      - Nigeria
      - Ghana TRC
      - Peru overview
      - Hybrid tribunals
      - Vetting
      - TC operational series
      - FA and TJ: O&A project
      - O&A papers (2 folders)
      - Outreach
      - Unfoldered miscellaneous, including Liberia materials, articles
      - Liberia, 2005
      - TRC workshop and planning
      - Liberia reference (trip reports)
      - Brussels, Geneva, Liberia, 2006
      - Liberia (to-do)
      - Essentials course, February 2006
      - TRC work plans
      - Liberia materials (4 folders)
    - ICTJ Personnel and miscellaneous unfiled (Box 60)
      - ICTJ benefits and Priscella Hayner records
      - Professional development
      - ICTJ interns
      - ICTJ personnel
      - ICTJ teams
      - European Union reference and information
      - UN DPA
      - National Security Archine
      - Projects and Themes (9 folders)
      - People/personnel files: ICTJ interns
      - General resources
      - Priscilla Hayner files: writing/talk/CU (6 folders)
      - General ICTJ information and administration (7 folders)
      - Fundraising, 2004-2006
      - Country information, 2005 (5 folders)
      - Events attended, 2005-2006 (12 folders)
  - Staff files: Marieke Wierda (Box 61)
    Prosecutions Unit, New York office.
    - Notebooks (21)
    - Business cards
    - Audio cassette: Special Court for Sierra Leone Independence
    - 3.5 floppy disks (40)
    - Columbia Survey draft
    - Rent
    - Bar registration
    - Affidavits: Bar exam
    - Work documents
    - 28 notebooks (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous loose items
    - Travel files, 2004-2006 (11 folders)
    - Bank
    - TIAA-CREFF enrollment kit
    - Wierda's American Express
    - Security Council debates
    - UGA/ICC files (Box 63-64)
    - Sudan files (Box 65)
    - First Annual Report of the President of the Special Court for Sierra Leone (bound) (Box 66)
    - Mandate holders for the Special Procedures of the Human Rights Council, 2008
    - Ex-Combatant Views of the TRC and the Special Court in Sierra Leone
    - Interim Report on the Special Court for Sierra Leone, 2005
    - Truth Commissions, 2006
    - Diploma de Postitulo derechos humanos y procesos de democratizacion, 2007
    - Analisis de delitos contra los derechos humanos y estrategias para su investigacion
    - Committee on the Echelon Interception System, November 2000
    - General articles/international
    - Parliamentary Monitoring Mechanism on Intelligence Agencies, October 1995
    - Domestic Prosecutions and Transitional Justice, South Africa, 2005
    - Global Dialogues on Transitional Justice: Assessing the Impact of Truth Commissions, 2003
    - Symposium at Asia Society, Transitional Justice in Cambodia, September 2003
    - ICTJ/AIHRC Seminar on Transitional Justice in Afghanistan, March 2003
    - Memoria y justicia para la inclusion, 2005
    - Introduction to Transitional Justice: Basic Training Module, 2004
    - Prison reform
    - International and local lessons in truth seeking, Greensboro and the US, 2006
    - Conference and research papers, 2003-2006 (3 folders)
    - Sierra Leone binders (2 folders)
    - Articles, statements, publications, and programs (7 folders)
    - Transitional Justice Alliance
    - ICTJ program staff
    - Directory
    - Articles, publications, drafts, documents (6 folders)
  - Media and audiovisual materials (Box 67-76)
- Accession (2010-0140), (2 boxes)
  - LaCie 1TB drive with electronic files of Liberia TRC hearings tapes/exports/conversions, Resource Discs and new audiovisual material (Box 77,77A,78)
  - Liberia TRC hearings: second batch of mini-DV tapes (in several boxes; see FMP database inside folder on drive)
  - TJ-PB mini-DV tapes (several boxes)
  - 4 wallets of resource discs (see Excel database report inside folder on drive)
  - Audiocassettes converted to MP3 files (see Excel log)
  - Various CDs and DVDs (see Excel log)
  - Liberia TRC handbook for workshop (original printed version in blue binder)
  - Wallet of mostly raw photos and some videos, all processed
  - 4 notebooks
  - VHS tape labels
- Accession (2010-0111), (1 box)
  Includes electronic files and drives as well as audiovisual material from the ICTJ Iraq Tribunal. Hard drive has been removed and transferred to Duke's Moving Image Archivist. This addition requires processing before use.
  - Audiovisual files, VCDs, VHS tapes (Box 79)